RG 004:139, Suffield Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Suffield Probate Court records
1821-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Suffield District)
45.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1821-1924; Probate files, 1821-1975.
RG004_139
1911-011, 2011-091, 2011-092, T003294
Historical Note
Suffield, Hartford County, Town established in May 1674 as part of Massachusetts; annexed to Connecticut, May 1749; Parent Town: Part of Hampshire County, Massachusetts until 1749
The Suffield Probate District was constituted May 1821, from the Granby Probate District. The Suffield Probate District merged with the East Granby Probate District on January 3, 2007, and later with the Bloomfield and Windsor Locks Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #3 Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bloomfield, East Granby, Suffield, and Windsor Locks.
Town of Suffield, Probate District chronology:
1674 - May 1749, Hampshire County Probate Jurisdiction
May 1749 - May 1821, Hartford District
May 1807 - May 1821, Granby District (Suffield section lying west of the mountain)
May 1821 - January 2, 2007, Suffield District
January 3, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Suffield - East Granby District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #3 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, volumes 1-21, 1821-1924. Contact the probate court to access original record books after volume 21. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1821-1975. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1821-1947 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accessions 2011-091 are numnbered 1 to 21. There are two volumes numbered 19.
Probate files in accession 1911-011 are arranged alphabetically.
Probate files in accession T003294 are arranged alphabetically.
Probate files in accession 2011-092 are arranged as received from the Probate Court.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1911-011 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-092.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Suffield
Places:
Suffield (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-091, Record books, 1821-1942, and Accession 2011-092, Probate files, 1897-1975, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED pending review by State Archives staff as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-7, 10, 12, 14, 16, 17, 19, 1821-1920; probate files, 1821-1880 (Accession 1911-011); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1911-011 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 28, 1911 (1821-1894); January 10, 1930 (1843-1928); February 26, 1937 (1843-1935); September 12, 1947 (1878-1938); December 10, 1953 (1902-1947). There were interfiled into one alphbetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-091 and the probate files in accession 2011-092 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 10, 2011.
It is not known when the probate files in accession T003294 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Record books, 1821-1942; 10.5 cubic feet (22 volumes); 2011-091
  - Records, 1821-1828 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1828-1840 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1840-1846 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1846-1853 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1853-1864 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1864-1875 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1875-1885 (Volume 7)
  - Orders and decrees, 1875-1892 (Volume 8)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Bonds, 1881-1915 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1886-1894 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1892-1899 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1894-1899 (Volume 12)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1899-1905 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1899-1905 (Volume 14)
  - Orders and decrees, 1905-1912 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1905-1910 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1910-1915 (Volume 17)
  - Orders and decrees, 1912-1918 (Volume 18)
  - Bonds, 1916-1942 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1915-1920 (Volume 19)
  - Orders and decrees, 1918-1924 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1920-1924 (Volume 21)
- Probate files, 1821-1947; 19 cubic feet; 1911-011
  - Adams - Allen, T. (Drawer 1)
  - Allen, U. - Austin, Hattie (Drawer 2)
  - Austin, Henry - Ballantine (Drawer 3)
  - Bancroft - Biggerstaff (Drawer 4)
  - Biggs - Briggs (Drawer 5)
  - Bristol - Bugbee (Drawer 6)
  - Buneski - Carr (Drawer 7)
  - Carrier - Clark, A. (Drawer 8)
  - Clark, B. - Cooper (Drawer 9)
  - Copley - Cummins (Drawer 10)
  - Curtin - Dibble (Drawer 11)
  - Dickenson - Dunn (Drawer 12)
  - Dutton - Fish (Drawer 13)
  - Fitch - Frost, C. (Drawer 14)
  - Frost, D. - Fuller, S. (Drawer 15)
  - Fuller, T. - Gillett, E. (Drawer 16)
  - Gillett, F. - Gregg, H. (Drawer 17)
  - Gregg, I. - Hale (Drawer 18)
  - Haley - Harmon, C. (Drawer 19)
  - Harmon, D. - Hastings, D. (Drawer 20)
  - Hastings, E. - Hauser (Drawer 21)
  - Hayden - Holcomb, H. (Drawer 22)
  - Holcomb, I. - Ives (Drawer 23)
  - Jackson - Kendall, G (Drawer 24)
  - Kendall, H. - Kent, Sidney (Drawer 25)
  - Kent, Stella - King, G. (Drawer 26)
  - King, H. - Knox (Drawer 27)
  - King, H. - Knox (Drawer 28)
  - Lester - Loomis, Ellen (Drawer 29)
  - Loomis, Emily - Los (Drawer 30)
  - Lovell - Mann (Drawer 31)
  - Marciniak - Miller, I. (Drawer 32)
  - Miller, J. - Murphy (Drawer 33)
  - Nash - Northway (Drawer 34)
  - Norton - Orr, S. (Drawer 35)
  - Orr, T. - Pease, G. (Drawer 36)
  - Pease, H. - Phelps, C. (Drawer 37)
  - Phelps, D. - Pinney (Drawer 38)
  - Pira - Pomeroy, N. (Drawer 39)
  - Pomeroy, O. - Read, L. (Drawer 40)
  - Read, M. - Rice, E. (Drawer 41)
  - Rice, F. - Rising (Drawer 42)
  - Roberts - Russell, A. (Drawer 43)
  - Russell, B. - Scott (Drawer 44)
  - Second - Sheldon, M. (Drawer 45)
  - Sheldon, N. - Sikes, S. (Drawer 46)
  - Sikes, T. - Smith, T. (Drawer 47)
  - Smith, U. - Spencer, E. (Drawer 48)
  - Spencer, F. - Spencer, Louise (Drawer 49)
  - Spencer, Lucina - Sutton (Drawer 50)
  - Sutula - Todd (Drawer 51)
  - Toelken - Vietts (Drawer 52)
  - Wadsworth - Warner, I. (Drawer 53)
  - Warner, J. - Waite, M. (Drawer 54)
  - White, N. - Woodbury (Drawer 55)
  - Woodruff - Wysocki (Drawer 56)
  - Yancey - Zukowski; Miscellaneous (Drawer 57)
- Inventory Control Book, 1821-1947; T003073
  Index of the five accessions of probate files merged into accession 1911-011
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, circa 1930-1952; 5.25 cubic feet; T003294
  There is no index for this accession
  - Adams - Birmingham (Drawer 1)
  - Bissel - Cain (Drawer 2)
  - Campbell - Courteau (Drawer 3)
  - Cowles - Fleming (Drawer 4)
  - Fogg - Gilligan (Drawer 5)
  - Glukowski - Hastings, L. (Drawer 6)
  - Hastings, M. - Keohane (Drawer 7)
  - King - Lennon (Drawer 8)
  - Leonard - Mearkle (Drawer 9)
  - Merrill - Pease (Drawer 10)
  - Orr - Prekop (Drawer 11)
  - Pye - Scott (Drawer 12)
  - Sikes - Spear (Drawer 13)
  - Spencer - Street (Drawer 14)
  - Strong - Upson (Drawer 15)
  - Van Horn - Zukowski (Drawer 16)
- Probate files, 1897-1975; 16 cubic feet; 2011-092
  Files arranged as received from Probate Court
  - Probate files (Drawer 1-16)